In an earlier video, I had
在早期的视频中(字幕翻译：中国海洋大学，仇志金)
said that PCA can be
我曾经说过，PCA在某些情况下可以
sometimes used to speed up the running time of a learning algorithm.
加快学习算法的执行效率
In this video, I'd like
在该视频中
to explain how to actually
我要去讲解实际情况下如何去做
do that, and also say
也就是说
some, just try to give
尝试着给一些建议
some advice about how to apply PCA.
如何去应用PCA算法
Here's how you can use PCA to speed up a learning algorithm,
下面讲解如何使用PCA算法来提高学习算法
and this supervised learning algorithm
对监督学习算法
speed up is actually the most
进行学习算法加速
common use that I
我个人常常采用PCA算法
personally make of PCA.
Let's say you have a supervised
比如说，你有一个
learning problem, note this is
监督学习算法，值的注意的是
a supervised learning problem with inputs
该监督学习算法
X and labels Y, and
需要输入X和标签Y
let's say that your examples
如果说，在你的例子中
xi are very high dimensional.
xi是有非常高的维度
So, lets say that your examples, xi are
比如说
10,000 dimensional feature vectors.
xi是10,000维的特征向量
One example of that, would
比如说
be, if you were doing some computer
你要解决一些关于
vision problem, where you have
可视化信息处理
a 100x100 images, and so
你有一个100*100的图片
if you have 100x100, that's 10000
如果是100*100，则就会有
pixels, and so if xi are,
10000个像素点，所以xi
you know, feature vectors
你知道，特征向量
that contain your 10000 pixel
包含10,000个像素
intensity values, then
亮度值，
you have 10000 dimensional feature vectors.
所以你将要处理10,000维的特征矩阵
So with very high-dimensional
对于像这种的高维
feature vectors like this, running a
特征矩阵
learning algorithm can be slow, right?
运行学习算法时将变的非常慢，不是吗?
Just, if you feed 10,000 dimensional
如果你要使用10,000维的
feature vectors into logistic regression,
特征矩阵进行逻辑回归
or a new network, or support vector machine or what have you,
或一个新的网络，或支持向量机，或你想要的操作
just because that's a lot of data,
因为数据量太大
that's 10,000 numbers,
包含10,000成员
it can make your learning algorithm run more slowly.
将会造成你的学习算法运行非常的慢
Fortunately with PCA we'll be
幸运的时，PCA算法
able to reduce the dimension of
可以减少要处理
this data and so make
数据的维度
our algorithms run more
从而使得算法更加高效
efficiently. Here's how you
至于如何去做
do that. We are going
我们首先
first check our labeled
观察已经被标记的训练集
training set and extract just
和只抽取输入的参数
the inputs, we're just going to extract the X's
我们只抽取出X
and temporarily put aside the Y's.
把Y先临时放一边
So this will now give us
所以我们目前得到
an unlabelled training set x1
一个无标签的训练集x1
through xm which are maybe
到xm，这些数据集可能是
there's a ten thousand dimensional data,
一万维的数据
ten thousand dimensional examples we have.
在我们一万维的样本中
So just extract the input vectors
仅仅抽取出了输入的向量
x1 through xm.
x1 到 xm
Then we're going to apply PCA
此时，我们继续使用PCA
and this will give me a
将要使用一个
reduced dimension representation of the
低维的数据来代表
data, so instead of
取代
10,000 dimensional feature vectors I now
10,000维的特征向量
have maybe one thousand dimensional feature vectors.
可能我只需要一千维的特征向量
So that's like a 10x savings.
这样就是一个10倍的储存量
So this gives me, if you will, a new training set.
所以这样就给我们，如果你想要的话，一个新的训练集
So whereas previously I might
之前我可能
have had an example x1, y1,
有一个样本x1, y1
my first training input, is now represented by z1.
我之前的训练集的输入，现在用z1来取代
And so we'll have a
因此，我们将要
new sort of training example,
使用新的方式对训练集进行表达
which is Z1 paired with y1.
Z1 与 y1 进行对应
And similarly Z2, Y2, and so on, up to ZM, YM.
相似的Z2, Y2等等，直到 ZM, YM
Because my training examples are
因为我的训练样本是
now represented with this much
新的方式表示
lower dimensional representation Z1, Z2, up to ZM.
该方式是低维的，Z1, Z2, 到 ZM
Finally, I can take this
最终，我可以使用
reduced dimension training set and
这个低维的训练集
feed it to a learning algorithm maybe
去使用神经网络算法
a neural network, maybe logistic
或者是逻辑回归算法
regression, and I can
我可以
learn the hypothesis H, that
学习假设函数H
takes this input, these low-dimensional
根据输入，使用低维
representations Z and tries to make predictions.
的Z，尝试去进行预测
So if I were using logistic
所以，如果我使用逻辑回归
regression for example, I would
我将要
train a hypothesis that outputs, you know,
训练一个获得输出的假设函数，你知道
one over one plus E to
1加上一个E的
the negative-theta transpose
负的theta的转置
Z, that
Z，这样
takes this input to one these
输入一个Z矩阵
z vectors, and tries to make a prediction.
就可以尝试去进行预测
And finally, if you have
最终，如果你
a new example, maybe a new
有一个新的样本，可能是一个
test example X. What
新的测试样本X，
you do is you would
你要做的是
take your test example x,
你将要使用测试样本的x
map it through the same mapping
通过PCA的映射关系
that was found by PCA
进行映射
to get you your corresponding z.
获得对应的z
And that z then gets
获得z后
fed to this hypothesis, and this
把z带入到假设函数中
hypothesis then makes a
这个假设函数
prediction on your input x.
可以预测你输入的x
One final note, what PCA does
最后，PCA如何
is it defines a mapping from
定义一个映射
x to z and
从x到z
this mapping from x to
这个映射从x到
z should be defined by running
z应该被定义
PCA only on the training sets.
只在训练集上执行PCA
And in particular, this mapping that
尤其特别的是，这个映射是
PCA is learning, right, this
PCA的学习过程，没错
mapping, what that does is it computes the set of parameters.
这个映射，是计算一系列的参数
That's the feature scaling and mean normalization.
是特征的缩放和归一化过程
And there's also computing this matrix U reduced.
这里经常计算矩阵Ureduced
But all of these things that
但所有这些事情
U reduce, that's like a
计算矩阵Ureduced，就像
parameter that is learned
通过学习PCA得到的参数
by PCA and we should
我们应该
be fitting our parameters only to
拟合这些参数，仅仅在
our training sets and not
训练集上
to our cross validation or test sets and
而不是交叉验证或者在测试集上
so these things the U reduced
求解Ureduced这些事情
so on, that should be
就是说
obtained by running PCA only on your training set.
只在训练集上运行，得到的PCA
And then having found U reduced, or having found the parameters for feature
然后，找到Ureduced，或者找到特征参数
scaling where the mean normalization
缩放，即归一化
and scaling the scale
和缩放规模
that you divide the features by to get them on to comparable scales.
使得你划分的特征，让他们具有可比性
Having found all those parameters
找到所有的参数
on the training set, you can
在训练集上
then apply the same mapping to other examples that may be
于是，你可以应用这相同的映射到其他样本中
In your cross-validation sets or
如在你交叉验证集
in your test sets, OK?
或者你的测试集，OK？
Just to summarize, when you're
总结一下，当你
running PCA, run your
在运行PCA时，运行
PCA only on the
PCA仅仅在
training set portion of the
训练集部分的数据
data not the cross-validation set or the test set portion of your data.
不可以是在交叉验证集和测试集数据部分
And that defines the mapping from
定义了x到z的映射
x to z and you can
你可以
then apply that mapping to
应用这个映射到
your cross-validation set and your
你的交叉验证集
test set and by the
和你的测试集
way in this example I talked
顺便说一下，在这个例子中，
about reducing the data from
我讲了减少一万维的数据
ten thousand dimensional to one
到
thousand dimensional, this is actually
一千维的数据，实际上
not that unrealistic. For many
这不是说不现实的
problems we actually reduce the dimensional data. You
在许多问题上，我们需要去减少数据的维度
know by 5x maybe by 10x
你可以减少5倍或者10倍
and still retain most of the variance and we can do this
仍然保留较大的方差，我们这样做可以
barely effecting the performance,
几乎不影响性能
in terms of classification accuracy, let's say,
分类精度，比方说
barely affecting the classification
几乎不影响分类
accuracy of the learning algorithm.
算法的准确度
And by working with lower dimensional
而且通过较低的维度
data our learning algorithm
数据，我们的学习算法
can often run much much faster.
通常运行的非常快
To summarize, we've so far talked
总而言之,我们到目前为止
about the following applications of PCA.
我们讨论下PCA应用
First is the compression application where
首先，压缩应用
we might do so to reduce
我们可能需要这样做，
the memory or the disk space
来减少存储器或硬盘空间
needed to store data and we
用来存储数据
just talked about how to
我们仅仅讨论如何
use this to speed up a learning algorithm.
使用该方法去加速学习算法
In these applications, in order
在该应用中，
to choose K, often we'll
需要去选择一个K，我们经常
do so according to, figuring
这样做的依据是，计算出
out what is the percentage of
方差保留的百分比
variance retained, and so
通常
for this learning algorithm, speed
这种学习算法
up application often will retain 99%  of the variance.
加速应用，需要保留99%的方差
That would be a very typical choice
这是一种非常典型的
for how to choose k. So
如何去选择k的方式
that's how you choose k for these compression applications.
所以对于压缩应用，就是你如何选择k
Whereas for visualization applications
而对于可视化应用
while usually we know
虽然我们通常知道
how to plot only two dimensional
如何去标记二维数据
data or three dimensional data,
或三维数据
and so for visualization applications, we'll
对于可视化应用程序
usually choose k equals 2
我们通常选择k等于2
or k equals 3, because we can plot
或者k等于3，因为我们可以
only 2D and 3D data sets.
标记2D和3D数据集
So that summarizes the main
总结一下，
applications of PCA, as well
应用PCA的主要是
as how to choose the
如何去选择
value of k for these different applications.
k值，对于不同的应用
I should mention that
我必须提出
there is often one frequent misuse of PCA and
PCA算法经常被滥用
you sometimes hear about others
有时候你会听到
doing this hopefully not too often.
别人希望这样去做，不是太频繁
I just want to mention this so that you know not to do it.
我只是仅仅提一下，以至于你知道不要这样去做
And there is one bad use of
这里有一个非常坏的PCA应用
PCA, which iss to try to use it to prevent over-fitting.
iss曾经尝试使用PCA去防止过拟合
Here's the reasoning.
这里的推理
This is not a great
不是非常棒的
way to use PCA,
使用PCA方式
but here's the reasoning behind
但该方法背后的原因是
this method, which is,you know
你知道
if we have Xi, then
如果我们有Xi
maybe we'll have n features, but
可能我们将要有n个特征
if we compress the data, and
但是如果我们压缩这些数据
use Zi instead
使用Zi替代
and that reduces the number
减少
of features to k, which
特征数量k
could be much lower dimensional. And
可以得到很低的维度
so if we have a much smaller
因此，如果你有一个非常少的
number of features, if k
数量的特征
is 1,000 and n is
比如k是1,000
10,000, then if we have
n是10,000
only 1,000 dimensional data, maybe
但是我们只有1,000维的数据
we're less likely to over-fit
可能我们不太可能过拟合
than if we were using 10,000-dimensional
相反，如果我们使用10,000维的数据
data with like a thousand features.
1,000个特征
So some people think
一些人就会认为
of PCA as a way to prevent over-fitting.
PCA是一种防止过拟合的方法
But just to emphasize this
但是，仅仅强调这一点
is a bad application of PCA
是PCA的非常糟糕的应用
and I do not recommend doing this.
我不建议去这样做
And it's not that this method works badly.
这并不是说该方法工作不好
If you want to use
如果你想去
this method to reduce the dimensional
使用该方法去减少数据维度
data, to try to prevent over-fitting,
防止过拟合
it might actually work OK.
它可能效果也会很好
But this just is not
但是，这仅仅
a good way to address
不是一种非常好的方式
over-fitting and instead, if you're
处理过拟合问题，相反，如果
worried about over-fitting, there is
你担心过拟合
a much better way to address
这有一种非常好的方式去防止过拟合发生
it, to use regularization instead of
使用规则化来代替使用PCA
using PCA to reduce the dimension of the data.
来减少数据维度
And the reason is, if
理由是，
you think about how PCA works,
你想一下，PCA是如何工作的
it does not use the labels y.
它不需要使用标签y
You are just looking
你仅仅是使用
at your inputs xi, and you're
输入的xi
using that to find a
你是使用它去寻找
lower-dimensional approximation to your data.
低维对你的数据进行近似
So what PCA does,
所以PCA
is it throws away some information.
会舍掉一些信息
It throws away or reduces the
它扔掉或减少
dimension of your data without
数据的维度
knowing what the values of y
不关心y值是什么
is, so this is probably
所以这可能是较好的使用PCA
okay using PCA this way
这种方式
is probably okay if, say
可能是好的
99 percent of the
99%的
variance is retained, if you're keeping most
方差信息被保留，如果你保持
of the variance, but
较多的方差
it might also throw away some valuable information.
但是，它也可能会丢掉更多的有价值的信息
And it turns out that
事实证明
if you're retaining 99% of
如果你保留了99%的方差
the variance or 95%
或者95%的方差
of the variance or whatever, it
诸如此类
turns out that just using
事实证明，只使用
regularization will often give
规则化常常会给你带来
you at least as good
至少一样好的效果
a method for preventing over-fitting
来防止过拟合
and regularization will often just
规则化
work better, because when you
常常会工作的更好，因为
are applying linear regression or logistic
当你是应用线性回归或者逻辑回归
regression or some other method
或其它的一些方法
with regularization, well, this minimization
进行规则化时，这个最小化问题
problem actually knows what the
实际上是知道
values of y are, and
y的值
so is less likely to throw
所以不太可能
away some valuable information, whereas
损失掉一些值的信息
PCA doesn't make use
然而，PCA不使用
of the labels and is more
标签
likely to throw away valuable information.
更有可能丢失一些值的信息
So, to summarize, it is
因此，总结一下
a good use of PCA, if your
使用PCA比较好的方式
main motivation to speed up
你关心
your learning algorithm, but using
学习算法的速度，
PCA to prevent over-fitting, that
但是使用PCA去防止过拟合
is not a good use of
不是一种非常好的方式
PCA, and using regularization instead
使用规则化来代替
is really what many people
正确的，许多人
would recommend doing instead. Finally,
建议这样取代，最后
one last misuse of PCA.
减少对PCA的滥用
And so I should say PCA is a very useful algorithm,
所以我应该说主成分分析是一种非常有用的算法,
I often use it for the compression on the visualization purposes.
我经常使用它来达到压缩可视化文件的目的
But, what I sometimes
但是，我有时候发现
see, is also people sometimes
一些人在有时候
use PCA where it shouldn't be.
在不需要使用PCA的时候使用PCA
So, here's a pretty common thing that
因此，这有一个很常见的事情
I see, which is if someone
我发现，
is designing a machine-learning system,
如果一些人在设计机器学习系统时，
they may write down the
他们可能写下
plan like this: let's design a learning system.
这样一个计划：让我们设计一个学习系统
Get a training set and then,
获得训练集
you know, what I'm going to
你知道，我们将要
do is run PCA, then train
执行PCA
logistic regression and then test on my test data.
接下来，训练逻辑回归，然后测试我们的数据
So often at the very
所以，经常
start of a project,
在一个项目开始时
someone will just write out a
一些人会写下
project plan than says lets
一个工程计划
do these four steps with PCA inside.
包括PCA在内的四步计划
Before writing down a project
在写下项目计划之前
plan the incorporates PCA like
结合PCA
this, one very good
一个非常好的问题被提出
question to ask is, well, what if we
如果我们
were to just do the whole
如何直接去做
without using PCA.
而不使用PCA
And often people do not
通常在人们
consider this step before
不考虑这一步
coming up with a complicated project plan and
在提出一个复杂的项目计划
implementing PCA and so on.
和实现PCA之前
And sometime, and so specifically,
有些情况下，具体地说
what I often advise people
我常常建议人们
is, before you implement
在实现PCA之前
PCA, I would first
我首先建议
suggest that, you know, do
你知道
whatever it is, take whatever it
无论做什么
is you want to do and first
执行一切你想做的
consider doing it with your
首先考虑
original raw data xi, and
你最原始的数据xi
only if that doesn't do
只有不去做你想要的
what you want, then implement PCA before using Zi.
然后，在使用Zi之前，应用PCA
So, before using PCA you know,
因此，使用PCA之前
instead of reducing the dimension
代替减少数据维度
of the data, I would consider
而应该好好考虑
well, let's ditch this PCA step,
让我们抛弃PCA这一步
and I would consider, let's
我需要考虑
just train my learning algorithm
仅仅在我的原始数据上
on my original data.
训练学习算法
Let's just use my original raw
让我们仅仅使用我原始的
inputs xi, and I would
输入数据xi
recommend, instead of putting
我建议，取代
PCA into the algorithm, just
把PCA放入到算法中
try doing whatever it is you're doing with the xi first.
首先去尝试仅仅使用xi
And only if you have
除非
a reason to believe that doesn't
你认为存在一个原因导致不能工作
work, so that only if your
比如
learning algorithm ends up
你的学习算法结束
running too slowly, or only if
运行太慢
the memory requirement or the
或者内存
disk space requirement is too large,
或者硬盘空间需要太大
so you want to compress your
因此你需要去压缩
representation, but if only
你的表示方法
using the xi doesn't work,
但是如果仅仅使用xi不能正常工作
only if you have evidence or strong
只有如果你有证据
reason to believe that using
或强有力的原因认为
the xi won't work, then implement
使用xi不能工作
PCA and consider using the compressed representation.
此时使用PCA，来考虑进行压缩
Because what I do see, is
因为我所看到的
sometimes people start off with
有时候，一些人
a project plan that incorporates PCA
开始做项目计划
inside, and sometimes they,
总是把PCA包含在里面
whatever they're
有时候，他们
doing will work just
做的非常好
fine, even with out using PCA instead.
即使没有使用PCA在里面
So, just consider that
因此，仅仅考虑
as an alternative as well, before you
作为一种替代选择
go to spend a lot of
在你花大量时间
time to get PCA in, figure
去获得PCA，
out what k is and so on.
计算出k等之前
So, that's it for PCA.
这就是主成份分析
Despite these last sets of
尽管最近的结论说
comments, PCA is an
PCA是
incredibly useful algorithm, when you
非常有用的算法
use it for the appropriate applications
当你在适当的应用程序使用它时
and I've actually used PCA pretty
实际上，我经常使用PCA
often and for me,
对我来说，非常频繁
I use it mostly to speed
我主要使用PCA
up the running time of my learning algorithms.
来提高我的学习算法的运行速度
But I think, just as
但是，我认为
common an application of PCA,
仅仅常见的应用可以使用PCA
is to use it to
常常用在
compress data, to reduce
压缩数据
the memory or disk space
减少对内存和硬盘空间需求
requirements, or to use it to visualize data.
或者用来处理图像数据
And PCA is one of
PCA是非常
the most commonly used and one
常用的方式之一
of the most powerful unsupervised learning algorithms.
最强大的无监督算法之一
And with what you've learned
你之前学过的知识
in these videos, I think hopefully
和在该视频学到的内容
you'll be able to implement
我希望你可以去
PCA and use them
通过所有的上述目的
through all of these purposes as well
来更好的使用PCA